DALE **HAYNIE**

(832) 995-9720 Daleray1231@gmail.com

I am currently bartending for one of the largest airport hospitality companies in the US. I have spent years in and out of the service industry and have decided to expand my skillset beyond flavor pairings and balanced cocktails. During the summer I enrolled in an online bootcamp for full stack web development, through UT Austin. Upon receiving my bootcamp certificate (late January 2024), I would be looking to take on new and exciting challenges to further grow my career as a web developer/programmer. I am eager and motivated to break into the IT industry. I know I still have so much to learn, but I do believe I have much to offer from a decade of customer service skills.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

8/2021 - PRESENT

OTG MANAGEMENT, IAH

BARTENDER

As a Bartender with OTG my duties were to provide guests with the best possible service in a clean and welcoming atmosphere.

My responsibilities were that of a bartender with high standards working in any upscale environment. With OTG I was required to display incredible flexibility, working in multiple different concepts(restaurants). This required quick thinking, ability to adjust, and working well under pressure. Not to mention needing exceptional customer service skills. Due to staffing issues, and poor management hires, often I was left to work out customer problems myself, which almost always resulted in a positive experience for my guests.

7/2018 - 05/2020

WALDEN ON LAKE HOUSTON COUNTRY CLUB

FOOD & BEVERAGE DIRECTOR (2020), BANQUET CAPTAIN (2019) BARTENDER/SERVER (2018)

As F&B Director at the country club my duties were integrated with almost every other department. I was responsible for our casual dining area (The 19th Hole), our beverage cart, the Main Dining Room, The Palmer Lounge (Event bar/dining), the snack bar at our swimming pool, as well as many catered marketing events. My duties included but are not limited to making schedules, filing invoices, maintaining vendor relations, ordering products, monthly inventory, collaboration with other department heads, and much more.

During my time with Walden Country Club, I quickly rose through the ranks driven by my ambition to succeed. Starting as a bartender/server, then Banquet Captain, and finally serving as the Food & Beverage Manager. This period of my career helped me to discover many untapped skills, as well as areas I could improve on. From early on as a bartender I enjoyed making people happy and providing them with a pleasant and professional experience. Clearly this did not go unnoticed as I was progressively given more responsibility, or "opportunity", and consistently produced exceptional results.

9/2014 - 1/2018

KONICA MINOLTA BUSINESS SOLUTIONS

OFFICE SYSTEMS PROFESSIONAL

As a service technician I was required to apply an array of skills to my regular work day. These skills include the following: Mechanical and Technical understanding, Problem Solving, Customer Service, Time Management, Inventory Management, Maintain Clean Professional Appearance

During my time with Konica Minolta I received annual reviews in which I attained above average scores in every category. I started with no experience but was able to excel in my position taking every opportunity to receive more training and certifications in my field.

3/2014 - 8/2014

HOUSTON RECREATION MANAGEMENT

POOL SUPERVISOR

As a Pool Supervisor I had experience in every aspect of this field. From being a summer lifeguard, to managing other lifeguards, I also had worked several years as a technician, so I had a vast understanding of the day to day. Some of the requirements of the job include:

Mechanical and Technical Comprehension, Attention to Detail, Staff Management, Time Management, Use of Toxic Chemicals, Safety Precaution, And required to lift up to 100 lbs.

During my employment with Houston Recreation Management I learned the importance of managing my workload. I had to be sure to visit each of my managed sites in a timely fashion, while at the same time keeping a close eye on detail and making sure all expectations were being met for both the other employees and the facility itself.

1/2012 - 2/2014

AQUATIC MANAGEMENT OF HOUSTON

POOL TECHNICIAN/LIFEGUARD/POOL MANAGER

Starting with this company as a Pool Cleaner I quickly found a passion for this industry and eventually worked in every position available in Swimming Pool Management. During this time I acquired an array of skills: Mechanical and Technical Comprehension, Attention to Detail, Staff Management, Time Management, Use of Toxic Chemicals, Safety Precaution, and required to lift up to 100 lbs.

During my employment with Aquatic Management of Houston I developed many new skills that I'm proud to say have helped to inspire my growth in the work force. The most notable difference this job made in my life is my keen eye for safety precautions. I am proud to say that I never experienced any injuries or accidents during my time in this industry. I am a firm believer that safety begins with taking the right precautions.

REFERENCES

Joshua Lujan (832) 585-3289
Former Food & Beverage Director, Walden on Lake Houston

Nick Turner (281) 254-1072 AGM, OTG Management

John Long (346) 435-6541 GM III, OTG Management

EDUCATION

UT Austin Bootcamp (Coding), Graduate January Graduated Atascocita High School, December 2008

CERTIFICATES

– TABC– –Food Handler Manager –

Qualified Mixologist (Texas School of Bartenders) –